Guide to the Joseph Brodsky Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Joseph Brodsky papers
1890-2004
1972-1996
GEN MSS 613
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
115.28
(228 boxes) + 3 broadside
The Joseph Brodsky Papers document the life and work of Russian-born poet, essayist and Nobel Laureate Joseph Brodsky, with a particular emphasis on the time period of his residence in the United States (1972-1996). The papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers (including legal, medical and financial records), audiovisual material, teaching material, student papers, newspaper clippings and printed ephemera, spanning the years 1890-2004, with the bulk of the material dating from the period 1972-1996.
Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-1996
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund from Lame Duck Books in 2004. One box was donated by the Estate of Joseph Brodsky in 2005.
According to a letter in her correspondence (April 1996), Ann Kjellberg (Joseph Brodsky's assistant and, after his death, literary executor) began to assemble an archive of Brodsky's papers in 1991. This effort continued after his death in 1996. Friends and associates of Brodsky (George Kline, Carl Proffer, Masha Vorobiov and others) sent Kjellberg originals and photocopies of papers to be included in the archive. Provenance of individual items can sometimes be traced by Kjellberg's or others' notes on the material.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Access to some material is restricted, as detailed in the following paragraphs. Consult the appropriate curator for more information.
Letters of Recommendation (Boxes 21-22), Student Papers (Boxes 127-131) and Restricted Papers (Boxes 214-217) are restricted until 2071.
The notebooks in Box 40 are partially restricted until 2071. Access to the original notebooks is restricted. A microfilm of unrestricted pages is available.
Boxes 168-169, 171-176, 220-225, and 232 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 218-219, 226 and 233-241: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies are available for electronic documents. Consult Access Services for further information. For other materials, reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on microfilm.
Associated Materials
Printed material received with the collection was removed for separate cataloging and can be accessed by searching the library's online catalog.
Joseph Brodsky, 1940-1996
Joseph Brodsky, Russian-born poet, essayist and Nobel Laureate, was born in Leningrad on May 24, 1940 to Aleksandr Ivanovich Brodskii and Mariia Moiseevna Brodskaia (nee Vol'pert). His birth was just one year before the start of the Leningrad Blockade; thus his early years were ones of extreme hardship. The Brodsky family's Jewish heritage exposed them to the anti-Semitic atmosphere of the post-war Soviet Union, causing Aleksandr Ivanovich to lose his rank in the Army and preventing Joseph from entering into the submarine academy. The communal apartment where Brodsky lived with his parents (and where his parents lived until their deaths) was memorialized in his essay "A room and a half."
Joseph Brodsky ended his formal schooling by walking out of his public school classroom at age fifteen and worked in a variety of places, including a factory, a morgue, and on geological expiditions. He began to write poetry in his teens and soon demonstrated a keen interest in translation. He taught himself Polish and English in order to translate poetry, including that of Czesław Miłosz and John Donne. Brodsky's Russian literary influences included Anna Akhmatova, Osip Mandelshtam, Boris Pasternak and Marina Tsvetaeva. His early writings in Russia were circulated in samizdat (self-published) collections, the most complete one compiled by Vladimir Maramzin.
Brodsky was arrested several times starting in 1961, tried in 1964 as a "social parasite" (tuneiadets), and sentenced to five years of labor in Norenskaia (a village in the Arkhangelsk Province of northern Russia). Brodsky lived in Norenskaia from March of 1964 to October of 1965 and wrote prolificly there. Brodsky's trial and sentence brought him increasing international attention when Frida Vigdorova's transcript was publicized in the Western media. It was also around this time that his poetry began to be compiled and published in the United States. Stikhotvoreniia i Poemy (Washington, D.C. & New York: Inter-Language Literary Associates) was published in in 1965, followed by Ostanovka v pustyne (New York: Izdatel'stvo imeni Chekhova) in 1970. Even after his release from Norenskaia, Brodsky continued to be at constant risk of arrest. In 1972 he was forced to emigrate when he was suddenly granted a visa (for which he had not applied) to emigrate to Israel. He had to leave Russia within a matter of weeks.
Brodsky traveled to Austria, where he stayed with W.H. Auden for several weeks, and to England before coming to the United Sates. He accepted a position as Poet in Residence at the University of Michigan (a post that Carl Proffer, founder of Ardis Publishing, was instrumental in securing). Brodsky taught at Michigan until 1981, when he accepted a permanent position on the faculty of Mount Holyoke College. He then divided his time between New York City and South Hadley, Massachusetts. He became a United States citizen in 1977. Brodsky never returned to Russia after emigrating, though later in his life political circumstances would have allowed it and his Russian readers clamored for it.
Among Brodsky's many awards and honors are a John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship (1977), a John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation award (1981), a National Book Critics Circle award (1986), the Nobel Prize in Literature (1987), France's Order of the Legion of Honor (1991), and honorary degrees from Yale University (1978), Dartmouth College (1989), and Oxford University (1991). He was Poet Laureate of the United States from 1991 to 1992.
Brodsky suffered from heart disease throughout his adult life and he had several open-heart surgeries. He died of heart failure on January 28, 1996.
During his lifetime, much of Brodsky's collected poetry and prose was published by Ardis in Ann Arbor, Michigan (Russian-language poetry) and Farrar, Straus and Giroux in New York (English-language poetry, English translations and prose collections). Brodsky's major publications from 1977 to 2000 include:
Chast' rechi: Stikhotvoreniia 1972-76 (Ardis, 1977)
Konets prekrasnoi epokhi: Stikhotvoreniia 1964-71 (Ardis, 1977)
V Anglii (Ardis, 1977)
A Part of Speech (Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1980)
Rimskie elegii (New York: Russica, 1982)
Novye stansy k Avguste: Stikhi k M.B., 1962-1982 (Ardis, 1983)
Less Than One: Selected Essays (Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1986)
Uraniia (Ardis, 1987)
To Urania: Selected Poems 1965-1985 (Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1988)
Watermark (Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1992)
On Grief and Reason: Essays (Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1995)
Peizazh s navodneniem (Dana Point, California: Ardis, 1996)
So Forth: Poems (Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1996)
Collected Poems in English, 1972-1999 (Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 2000)
Scope and Contents
The Joseph Brodsky Papers document the life and work of Russian-born poet, essayist and Nobel Laureate Joseph Brodsky. The papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers (including legal, medical and financial records), audiovisual material, teaching material, student papers, newspaper clippings and printed ephemera, spanning the years 1890-2004, with the bulk of the material dating from the period 1972-1996.
The papers document all aspects of Brodsky's professional life, including writings, appearances, readings, lectures, advocacy and relations with other literary figures. The research interest of the papers encompasses Russian-language poetry, the Soviet emigre experience, and poetry translation. Researchers interested in Brodsky's creative process will find much relevant material, including multiple drafts (many corrected) of poems and essays (including translations by Brodsky and others). Teaching material is present in small quantities and provides only sporadic documentation of Brodsky's career as an educator. Personal papers are also present and chiefly document immigration and other legal affairs.
Brodsky's work, while rarely political, reflects broad historical and political themes that defined his era: empire, emigration, and the relationship of the individual to the state. The trajectory of Brodsky's publishing and teaching is inextricable from the emigre experience, as his early works were censored in the Soviet Union and promoted by publishers and scholars in the United States. After the fall of the Soviet Union, the Russian literary public was able to "reclaim" Brodsky openly and his works (including Russian translations of his essays) were published there.
Brodsky's bilingual emigre identity is elucidated in his writings. A significant proportion of Brodsky's poetry was translated from Russian to English, often by multiple translators, and some poems exist in alternate versions. Brodsky's prose was also oft-translated: his early essays were written in Russian and translated into English, though most of his prose was written in English. While Brodsky's notes and corrections indicate engagement with the translation of his prose, it is evident that his commitment to and involvement in the translation of his poetry was profound.
Brodsky's personal papers document his bitter struggle with American and Soviet bureaucracies as he tried first to have his parents visit him in the United States and then to attend his father's funeral. After emigration, as evidenced particularly in his letters to editors, Brodsky lent his international acclaim to the cause of politically persecuted literary figures in the Soviet Union and elsewhere.
Brodsky's literary milieu, like his life and work, was transnational and multilingual. Correspondence, writings and audiovisual recordings document his close relationships with fellow Nobel Laureates Seamus Heaney, Czesław Miłosz and Derek Walcott and with English-language poets Anthony Hecht and Mark Strand, among others. Many of these poets translated Brodsky's poetry or dedicated poems to Brodsky in memorium. Hundreds of aspiring and accomplished Russian-language poets also sent him manuscripts, as evidenced in Writings of Others.
Arrangement
Organized into eleven series: I. Correspondence, 1964-2004. II. Writings, 1959-2000. III. Interviews and Speeches, 1974-1996. IV. Teaching Material and Student Papers, 1973-1995. V. Personal Papers, 1961-2000. VI. Photographs, 1890-2001. VII. Audiovisual Material, 1953-2002. VIII. Clippings, 1964-2002. IX. Printed Material, 1920-2003. X. Artwork, 1972-1986. XI. Papers of Others, 1912-2000.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, Russian -- 20th Century -- Archives; Emigration and immigration; Essays -- Translations into English; Essays -- Translations into Russian; Essays -- 20th Century; Nobel lectures, including presentation speeches and laureates' biographies; Nobel lectures, including presentation speeches and laureates' biographies; Nobel Prize winners; Poetry -- Translations into English; Poetry -- Translations into Russian; Poetry -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Poets, Russian -- 20th Century; Russian literature -- 20th Century; Russia -- Emigration and immigration; United States -- Emigration and immigration; Audiovisual materials; Audiocassettes; Clippings (information artifacts); Born digital; Electronic documents; Notebooks; Photographs; Samizdat -- Russia; Underground literature -- Soviet Union; Videotapes; Authors; Poets; Translators; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Barańczak, Stanisław, 1946-2014; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997; Brodskiĭ, Aleksandr; Brodski, Mariia; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-1996; Dovlatov, Sergeĭ, 1941-1990; Ėtkind, E. G. (Efim Grigorʹevich), 1918-1999; Golyshev, Viktor, 1937-; Hecht, Anthony, 1923-2004; Jangfeldt, Bengt, 1948-; Katilius, Elmira; Katilius, Ramunas, 1935-2014; Kjellberg, Ann; Kline, George L. (George Louis), 1921-2014; Mandelʹshtam, Nadezhda, 1899-1980; Mandelʹshtam, Osip, 1891-1938; Maramzin, Vladimir, 1934-; Miłosz, Czesław, 1911-2004; Picken, Margo; Proffer, Carl R.; Proffer, Ellendea, 1944-; Schiltz, Véronique, 1942-; Shults, Sergei; Solzhenit͡syn, Aleksandr Isaevich, 1918-2008; Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Sumerkin, Alexander, 1943-2006; Ufli︠a︡nd, Vladimir, 1937-; Verheul, Kees, 1940-; Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006; Vorobiov, Masha; Walcott, Derek, 1930-2017; Weissbort, Daniel, 1935-2013; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017; Ardis (Firm); Farrar, Straus, and Giroux; Poetry International (Festival)
- Correspondence, 1964-2004; Series I; 14.6; (35 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Correspondence is organized into three subseries: General Correspondence, Letters of Recommendation, and Ann Kjellberg Correspondence.
  Correspondence relates chiefly to Brodsky's writings, to readings and speaking engagements, to human rights advocacy (particularly as it relates to literary figures), and to affairs of the Russian emigre community in the United States.
  General Correspondence includes fan letters and letters soliciting Brodsky's opinion about manuscripts, primarily poems in English and in Russian. Manuscripts unaccompanied by letters, or accompanied by routine letters, are filed in Writings of Others (Boxes 103-121).
  While most of the correspondence dates from after Brodsky's 1972 emigration to the United States, there is some documentation of Brodsky's life in the Soviet Union and his emigration experience. A letter from Brodsky's father Aleksandr Brodskii (Box 3, folders 71-71, circa 1965) documents Brodskii's efforts to advocate for his son. Another 1965 letter in support of Brodsky (Chukovskii et al., Box 3, folder 92) is signed by over a dozen prominent literary figures. Letters from Sergei Shults (Box 14, folder 368) include notes about Brodsky's 1964 trial. A folder of telegrams to Brodsky in Kirchstetten in 1972 (Box 18, folders 470-497) demonstrates Brodsky's connections with and support from European and American literary figures at the time of his emigration.
  Correspondence from the years immediately after Brodsky's emigration chiefly document his search for a permanent position at a University and the translation and publication of his works. Letters from individuals such as Masha Vorobiov, George Kline (translator) and Carl Proffer (publisher) document their assistance to Brodsky in these domains.
  Later correspondence (from the 1980s and 1990s) addresses a wider range of topics and includes more purely professional requests (e.g. requests for appearances and requests to read manuscripts). The correspondence also documents Brodsky's continued commitment to advocacy on behalf of authors who are persecuted for political reasons.
  Little of the correspondence is purely personal in nature and there are few family letters.
  From the 1980s on, much of Brodsky's correspondence was managed by his assistants Aleksandr Sumerkin and Ann Kjellberg. Sumerkin managed the Russian-language correspondence, while Kjellberg managed the English-language correspondence. Correspondence managed by Brodsky's assistant Aleksandr Sumerkin is interfiled in General Correspondence.
  - General Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically. Files for correspondents identified by first name only and unidentified correspondents follow the main alphabetic listing.
    Scope and Contents
    General Correspondence is chiefly incoming but includes some outgoing letters. Folders that contain exclusively outgoing correspondence include "outgoing" in the folder title.
    - 2B: Polish American Quarterly, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "A" general, 1972-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2-8)
    - Aaron, Janet and Daniel, 1975-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Aaron, Jonathan, 1975-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1972-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Akhmadulina, Bella, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Aksenev, Vasilii, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Aleshkovskii, Iuz, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Alloy, Radda, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Alvarez, Alfred, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Ambassade de France, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - American Academy in Rome, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - American Poetry Center, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - American Poetry & Literacy Project, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - American Poetry Review, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Amnesty International, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Andreev, Mikhail, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Anghera, Maria, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ardis Publishers, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Proffer, Carl and Ellendea
    - Arndt, Walter, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Includes English translations of the poetry of Anna Akhmatova by Walter Arndt.
    - Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Artamonov, Sergei, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Ashkenazy, Vladimir, 1976 May (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Association of American Publishers, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Includes a letter from Iurii Kublanovskii to the Association of American Publishers.
    - Association of Literary Translators of Serbia, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Atkins, Ruth, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Includes poems by Atkins.
    - Auden, W.H., 1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Autrement Editions, 1995 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Averbakh, Elena, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Includes poems by Averbakh and an essay about Averbakh's interview of Brodsky.
    - "B" general, 1972-1995 (Box 2, Folder 38-45)
      Includes a poem by Iurii Batiaikin.
    - Bäckström, Annika, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Includes an essay by Bäckström on Joseph Brodsky and Bäckström's translation into Swedish of Pis'ma Dinastii Min'.
    - Bail, Murray, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Baldwin, Kate, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Balla, Philip, 1977-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Bankier, Joanna, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Barańczak, Stanisław, 1981-1995 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Includes Polish translations of several of Brodsky's poems by Eugeniusz Biedka.
    - Baryshnikov, Mikhail, third party (from Kazuko Oshima to Baryshnikov), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bayerische Akademie der Schönen Künste, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Belcher, Wendy, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Berberova, Nina, 1972-1987 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1974-1989 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Beverly, Eva, 1988
    - Beznosov, Edward, 1988-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Biedka, Eugeniusz, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      See also: Barańczak, Stanisław
    - Billington, James H., 1991 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Birbrajer, Julian, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Birkerts, Sven Peter, 1979-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Black, Sophia Cabot, 1984-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Black, Star, 1993 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      Includes poems by Black.
    - Blane, Andrew, 1975-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Blumenthal, Michael, 1985-1995 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Bok, Derek, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Botstein, Leon, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Bowdoin College, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Brodala, Tatiana, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
      Includes Polish translations by Brodala of several of Brodsky's poems.
    - Brodskii, Aleksandr and Maria (Joseph Brodsky's parents), circa 1965, 1973, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 71-72)
      Includes a letter from Aleksandr Brodskii to Comrade Tolstikov in support of Joseph Brodsky.
    - Brousselle, Samuel, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Bruder, Isabelle, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      Includes poems [by Bruder?].
    - Buch, Hans Christoph, 1979-1991 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Bullock, Susan, 1984-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
      Includes an essay by Bullock.
    - Buttafava, Giovanni and Elena, 1972-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - "C" general, 1972-1995 (Box 3, Folder 78-84)
      Includes English translations by Alex Cigale of Brodsky's poetry and poems by Jess Cloud and Sally Crabtree.
    - Caine, Mr., outgoing, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Calasso, Roberto, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Cambridge Poetry Festival, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Carugati, Giuliana, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Chalidze, Valerii, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Chertkov, [Leonid], 1974-1979, undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Chizhova, Elena, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      About a collection of Brodsky's poetry titled Pis'ma Rimskomu Drugu.
    - Chukovskii, Kornei et alia, third party, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 92)
      The letter supports the release of Brodsky from resettlement, to Prosecutor Mikhail Petrovich Maliarov from Kornei Chukovskii, Konstantin Paustovskii, Frida Vigdorova, Natalia Grudinina, Natalia Dolinina, Lidiia Chukovskaia, Anna Akhmatova, David Dar, B. Vakhtin, Evgenii Gnedin, Gleb Semenov, El'ga Linetskaia, T. Khmel'nitskaia, Vladimir Admoni, and Efim Etkind.
    - Clinton, Bill, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Coates, Jenny, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Columbia University, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Cravieri, Bernedetta, 1982-1995 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Cruise, Edwina, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Cuijak, Gustavo, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 98)
      Includes a playscript by Cuijak based partly on Brodsky's 1964 trial.
    - Culerrier, Pascal, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - "D" general, 1976-1995 (Box 4, Folder 100-102)
    - Dalsgaard, Mette, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Danojlić, Milovan, 1973-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Dediulin, Sergei, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Derieva, Regina, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 106)
      Includes poems by an unidentified author.
    - Detskaia Literatura, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - de Vio, Vittoria, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Dimpsey, Joanne, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Donde, Alexander, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Dooley, Kim, 1987-1995 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Dovlatov, Sergei, undated (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Drawicz, Andrzej, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Druzhba narodov, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - "E" general, 1973-1992 (Box 4, Folder 115-116)
    - [Ehrlich], Viktor, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Efimov, Igor'
      - Incoming, 1981-1995 (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - Outgoing, 1960s-1994 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Efimova, Marina, undated (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Eliot, Liz, 1972-1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Ellis, Joseph J., 1982-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - English, Maurice, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Eremin, Nikolai, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 124)
      Includes poems by Eremin.
    - Etkind, Efim
      - Incoming, 1973-1996 (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - Outgoing, 1973-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
        Includes drafts of the poems Konets prikrasnoi epokhi and Neofitsional'naia oda na den' rozhdeniia Professora E.G. Etkinda.
    - Ewing, Blair, 1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 127)
      Includes drafts of poems by Ewing.
    - "F" general, 1972-1995 (Box 5, Folder 128-131)
      Includes drafts of poems by an unidentified author (sent by A. Fridman).
    - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1975-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 132-135)
      See also: Strachan, Pat and Straus, Roger W., Jr.